<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jennifer Tesolin</title>
    <description>This is Jennifer Tesolin&#39;s personal web site. Located on this site are tutorials and tips for web developers.</description>
    <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.jenntesolin.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving a Wordpress blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will describe various ways to move WordPress, either to a different server or to Jekyll. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;steps-to-make-an-exact-copy&quot;&gt;Steps to make an exact copy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes all plugins, theses, posts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;download a copy of the database and save somewhere. Make a copy as a backup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do a search in the sql file for the current domain URL and replace with the new domain or ‘localhost’ &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;update the site location in the wp-config file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;import the sql database and add the user at the new location.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;upload your wordpress files and test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried other various methods including web apps, but those have caused problems such as not completely disconnecting the databases. In one instance WordPress core upgrade to the copied version, had also upgraded the first one as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-safest-way-to-move-but-not-exact&quot;&gt;The safest way to move (but not exact)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;download a copy of your themes, and plugins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;download an export of your post files. If your using a multisite, you will need to do this for each blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;download a fresh copy of Wordpress, and set up your plugins and themes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;import posts, map users making sure to check the box to download linked media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moving-to-jekyll&quot;&gt;Moving to jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to download a copy of your wp-content upload folder, you will also need your wordpress export file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, make sure you have Ruby on your machine. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/installation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Here is an install guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo gem install jekyll&lt;br /&gt;
sudo gem install jekyll-import&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a folder for your site and use the terminal to change to the folder your your site will be (&lt;code&gt;cd foldername&lt;/code&gt;).  Make sure the upload folder and a copy of your wordpress export is at the root of your new site folder. For demo purspoes, I will call it: wordpress.xml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this is set up, run the below command to import your blog into wordpress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll import wordpressdotcom --source wordpress.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, run the below command to build and preview the site. “–watch” will allow you to make chnages and have them update in your preview site automtically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll serve --watch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default preview site is: http://localhost:4000, but this can be changed from _config.yml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step is in this process is to push your files online. Move into the root of “_site”. These are the production ready files that should be moved to your server. An upcoming post will detail how to create a github pages site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/09/24/Moving-a-WordPress-Blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/09/24/Moving-a-WordPress-Blog/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use Double Twist to sync your iTunes library to a droid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post describes how you can sync your current iTunes media files to your android device. This tutorial was written and tested on Mac os X mavericks and a Nexus 5.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clean-up-your-current-itunes-library&quot;&gt;Clean up your current itunes library.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before moving any media files from an iTunes library to Android to play in any player, it’s best to get unlocked copies. For me the fastest (and legal non time consuming way) was to get iTunes music match enabled. Once it has finised setting up,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-remove-drm-from-your-music-with-itunes-match--mac-59271&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;follow this article on creating playlists&lt;/a&gt; to find locked files, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fix-with-itunes-match-playlists&quot;&gt;Fix with iTunes Match playlists&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All playlists had media kind music, then in the first one added I cloud status ineligible.  For music, this means that the bit rate used to import the media was under 92 kps and a match was not found in the iTunes Library. The best way to solve this error is to reimport from your CD if you want to keep using icloud or iTunes. Its not necessary to reimport if your just removing DRM. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next two playlists are similar to eachother. Once you have your playlists, select option and delete the files, but do NOT check delete from icloud. Make sure to move those files to your trash. You can then select all songs and re-download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my music from iTunes being quite large I set the music to redownload files while I was at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have those files re downloaded, go to view &amp;gt; show duplicates. Make sure that they are indeed duplicates, then delete from iCloud and iTunes. Its best to delete NON purchased items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;remove-duplicate-songs&quot;&gt;Remove duplicate songs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step is to find the duplicates in your music folder for iTunes using finder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This did not help my duplicate music problem in the double twist desktop app, but its best to check anyways. As always, make sure you have a backup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your sure your duplicates are gone, set up double twist on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-double-twist-on-your-computer&quot;&gt;Set-Up Double Twist on your computer.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-applications-to-mobile-and-desktop-devices&quot;&gt;Download applications to mobile and desktop devices.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to download for both desktop/laptop and mobile device. The files for teh desktop can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doubletwist.com/&quot;&gt;the offical website&lt;/a&gt;. The mobile version is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doubleTwist.androidPlayer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;play store&lt;/a&gt;. I just went ahead and the air sync add on since I do this often. With air sync go to mobile settings and get your four digit pin and enter on your desktop. You should now see your device their, if not, on you device select the option to broadcast. All add-ons are in app purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;set-up-desktop-app&quot;&gt;Set up desktop App&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, open the DoubleTwsit application. Choose your iTunes folder, the. Let it do its thing. A few times I had to close then reset program on desktop to see all playlists and files after editing in iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now select your device, choose your settings and sync. Be sure to note and fix any issues. These are usually being your file is locked by apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it!  It works pretty well but just note any adjustments to your playlist needs to be made in iTunes. Edits from double twist do not carry over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Con:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when you purchase airplay add on, you can no longer sync wired even when its disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;can ONLY use Itunes playlist. They have no way to sync chnages made in phone app to the iTunes library.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video playlists do not go to next item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;easy way to use a droid with your Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will take all iTunes Playlists (as long as file is unlocked).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugs encountered&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;even though no duplicates are in iTunes duplicate view, the library sometimes duplicates the files  (not in playlist but in the library view in music). I had no duplicates in finder. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hangs or sometimes crashes  on opening the desktop app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 15:34:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/07/16/Using-DoubleTwist-iTunes-and-Android/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/07/16/Using-DoubleTwist-iTunes-and-Android/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rebuilding the backend of my site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I am currently in the process of moving my WordPress blog over to using the Jekyll system. I will be trying to move it over before my hosting renews - this way I can try my hosting up at github pages or windows azure.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone is interested, I have some preview links below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, there will be a series of posts of my experience. Feel free to comment on your own experience using the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 18:34:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/05/22/rebuilding-the-backend-of-my-site/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/05/22/rebuilding-the-backend-of-my-site/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Updated: Raspberry Pi Media Server</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After trying quite a few Raspberry Pi operating systems and configurations, the new &lt;a title=&quot;Official site for the operating system&quot; href=&quot;http://www.rasplex.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;RasPlex&lt;/a&gt; is my choice for my home media centre. RasPlex was the best system which supports out of the box: WiFi, Bluetooth, hdmi monitor with analog speakers, and more. The best thing is the entire process took only 15 minutes!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Note: This is an update to the &lt;a title=&quot;A look at Raspmbc video streaming&quot; href=&quot;http://jenntesolin.com/blog/2013/09/05/a-look-at-raspmbc-video-streaming/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Raspmbc set-up article&lt;/a&gt;. RasPlex also requires the use of Plex Media Server which is also free, and easily connects to iTunes and various channels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set-up the SD card&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to &lt;a title=&quot;Rasplex installer downlaod page&quot; href=&quot;http://www.rasplex.com/get-started/rasplex-installers.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;download the installer&lt;/a&gt; for your Operating System onto your computer. They have installers available for Mac, Linux, and Windows, please be sure to read the notes on how to mount the installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you select the version of RasPlex you want, and then select your SD card drive (check disk utility for the name if your not sure). Finally, press &quot;update links&quot;, and when that is down &quot;click download&quot;.  It will ask you the location of the download, then when will display the download progress in the terminal. Once your all set-up, then press &quot;Write SD card&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jenntesolin.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Screen-Shot-2014-04-24-at-10.51.40-PM.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-609&quot; src=&quot;http://jenntesolin.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Screen-Shot-2014-04-24-at-10.51.40-PM-300x298.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2014-04-24 at 10.51.40 PM&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set-Up your Raspberry Pi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure all your devises (even Bluetooth and Wi-Fi) are connected, then boot your machine. Let it run the initial set-up, and reboot itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it reboots, follow the on screen instructions for set-up (note that only your keyboard will work so far). Some of the set-up options include: Bluetooth, WI-Fi, your Plex Media Server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you see the menu, press the left keyboard arrow to get to your settings, this is where you can set-up your audio settings, ssh access, and more. At set-up it will choose HDMI audio, just select analog to use stereo speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jenntesolin.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/IMG_1982.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-608&quot; src=&quot;http://jenntesolin.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/IMG_1982-300x199.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1982&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;199&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it! This this helps other people as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RasPlex Resources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RasPlex/RasPlex/wiki/Guides&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;RasPlex Github Guides Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rasplex.com/documentation/rasplex-setup-basics.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;RasPlex Set-Up Basics Documentation Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out their YouTube Trailer&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;small&gt;(it tells it better than me)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/C-A4Kxq3V0I?color=white&amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/04/24/updated-raspberry-pi-media-server/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/04/24/updated-raspberry-pi-media-server/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Removing cData from YQL queries</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When pulling data from xml items using YQL and getJSON, your application will unfortuntley not parse tags that have cdata. This post describe show to use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yqlblog.net/blog/category/tutorial/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;feed normalizer table&lt;/a&gt; to call all elements, even those that have cdata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;YQl Feed Normalizer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this table in my application, I worked off of the second example given on the YQL blog entry:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
SELECT * FROM feednormalizer&lt;br /&gt;
WHERE url=&#39;&lt;strong&gt;http://rss.news.yahoo.com/rss/topstories&lt;/strong&gt;&#39;&lt;br /&gt;
AND output=&#39;&lt;strong&gt;atom_1.0&lt;/strong&gt;&#39;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Note: the portion in bold beside the url is where your atom feed will go. Here is a list of valid outputs for the second bold portion:&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;small&gt;&#39;rss_0.91N&#39;|&#39;rss_0.93&#39;|&#39;rss_0.92&#39;|&#39;rss_1.0&#39;|&#39;rss_0.94&#39;|&#39;rss_2.0&#39;|&#39;rss_0.91U\rss_0.9&#39;|&#39;atom_1.0&#39;|&#39;atom_0.3&#39;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I added limit after the output field, and replaced * with the fields I wanted. The bold portions are the portions I personalized for my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YQL :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;SELECT &lt;strong&gt;entry.title,entry.link.href,entry.published,entry.category.term,entry.summary&lt;/strong&gt; FROM feednormalizer WHERE url= &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;http://jenntesolin.com/blog/feed/atom/&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; AND output=&amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;atom_1.0&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; &lt;strong&gt;LIMIT 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The full javaScript:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;//declare vars&lt;br /&gt;
  var blogLink = &#39;https://query.yahooapis.com/v1/public/yql?q=&#39; + encodeURIComponent(&#39;SELECT entry.title,entry.link.href,entry.published,entry.category.term,entry.summary FROM feednormalizer WHERE url= &amp;quot;http://jenntesolin.com/blog/feed/atom/&amp;quot; AND output=&amp;quot;atom_1.0&amp;quot; LIMIT 1&#39;)+&#39;&amp;amp;format=json&amp;amp;diagnostics=false&amp;amp;callback=?&#39;;&lt;br /&gt;
  //end variable declare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jQuery.noConflict();&lt;br /&gt;
  jQuery(document).ready(function($){&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; //Call blog feed&lt;br /&gt;
$.getJSON(blogLink, function(data){&lt;br /&gt;
  //get data&lt;br /&gt;
  var title =data.query.results.feed.entry.title.content;&lt;br /&gt;
  var link =data.query.results.feed.entry.link.href;&lt;br /&gt;
  var category =data.query.results.feed.entry.category.term;&lt;br /&gt;
  var published=data.query.results.feed.entry.published;&lt;br /&gt;
  var summary =data.query.results.feed.entry.summary.content;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; //display&lt;br /&gt;
  $(&#39;.blog-header&#39;).html(title);&lt;br /&gt;
  $(&#39;.blog-summary&#39;).html(summary);&lt;br /&gt;
  $(&#39;.blog-date&#39;).html(published);&lt;br /&gt;
  $(&#39;.blog-category&#39;).html(category);&lt;br /&gt;
  $(&#39;.blog-link&#39;).html(&#39;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;&#39;+link+&#39;&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Read more&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&#39;);&lt;br /&gt;
  });&lt;br /&gt;
  //end blog feed&lt;br /&gt;
  });&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTML Bootstrap 3.1 code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!-- Blog --&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-md-12&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;h1 class=&amp;quot;blog-header&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;blog-summary&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;badge blog-date&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;pull-right&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;label label-default blog-category&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;label label-primary blog-link&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;!-- /.Blog --&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yqlblog.net/blog/category/tutorial/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;YQL Feed Normalizer Table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jennifert/JavaScript-Demos/blob/master/YQL/cdata_blog_example.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/29/removing-cdata-from-yql-queries/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/29/removing-cdata-from-yql-queries/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating the Sticky footer with fixed navbar example with Bootstrap 3 using Emmet.IO</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post described how to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://emmet.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Emmet&lt;/a&gt; short codes to quickly create the bootstrap example: &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/examples/sticky-footer-navbar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sticky footer with fixed navbar&lt;/a&gt; using Bootstrap 3.  Feel free to read and implement suggestions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Sublime, select the Emmet code and press control + E (both Mac and PC)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Set up: Set up html, and body content, js&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A) Emmet Code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;html:5&amp;gt;(div.navbar.navbar-default.navbar-fixed-top&amp;gt;div.container&amp;gt;div.navbar-header&amp;gt;btn:r.navbar-toggle&amp;gt;span.sr-only{Toggle navigation}+span.icon-bar+span.icon+span.icon^a.navbar-brand{Welcome!}^div.collapse.navbar-collapse&amp;gt;ul.nav.navbar-nav&amp;gt;li*3&amp;gt;a^li.dropdown&amp;gt;a.dropdown-toggle{Dropdown }&amp;gt;b.caret^ul.dropdown-menu&amp;gt;li*3&amp;gt;a^li.divider+li.dropdown-header{Nav Header}+li*3&amp;gt;a^^^^^^^div.container&amp;gt;div.page-header&amp;gt;h1{Page Header Heer}^p.lead&amp;gt;lorem^^div#footer&amp;gt;div.container&amp;gt;p.text-muted{Copy Right Info}^^script:src{js/jquery-1.11.0.min.js}+script:src{js/bootstrap.min.js})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gist Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jennifert/9846832&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/jennifert/9846832&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Could not find emmet tag to define javascript source location, so just moved it between script tags. Please see step 8 at 1B below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B) Fill in the missing items/editing places:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Add role=navigation to : navbar.navbar-default.navbar-fixed-top&lt;br /&gt;
  2) At the toggle navigation &amp;lt;button&amp;gt; add: data-toggle=&amp;quot;collapse&amp;quot; data-target=&amp;quot;.navbar-collapse&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  3) Add link # or otherwise at: navbar-brand&lt;br /&gt;
  4) Add link, text and active item to: nav.navbar-nav remove&lt;br /&gt;
  5) In same class as above but in dropdown dropdown-toggle, add data-toggle=&amp;quot;dropdown&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  6) Edit h1 tag in: page-header class div&lt;br /&gt;
  7) Update Copy right Info&lt;br /&gt;
  8) Move js path that&#39;s between script tags to src=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Insert the rest of the header information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A) Emmet Code: Place course on line under &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;meta:vp+link:favicon+meta:compat+link:css{css/bootstrap.min.css}+link:css&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gist Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jennifert/9846855&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/jennifert/9846855&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B) Edit the following items:&lt;br /&gt;
  1) Favicon.ico if needed&lt;br /&gt;
  2) Change ie=7 to ie=edge in meta tag.&lt;br /&gt;
  3) In the style.css where you bootstrap is nested in, cut and paste the bootstrap stylesheet in place of styles.css.&lt;br /&gt;
  4) In between the updated bootstrap css and styles.css, paste your conditional comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!--[if lt IE 9]&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;https://oss.maxcdn.com/libs/html5shiv/3.7.0/html5shiv.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;https://oss.maxcdn.com/libs/respond.js/1.4.2/respond.min.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;lt;![endif]--&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5) In the file styles.css paste the bootstrap example styles from: http://getbootstrap.com/examples/sticky-footer-navbar/sticky-footer-navbar.css&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/28/sticky-footer-with-fixed-navbar-example-with-bootstrap-3-and-emmet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/28/sticky-footer-with-fixed-navbar-example-with-bootstrap-3-and-emmet/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving from an iOS Device to Android (iCloud)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Admittedly moving from an iOS device to an android device can seem a bit daunting, especially if you use iCloud for all your syncing. Thankfully there are a few apps on the Google play store that help connect your droid to icloud!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Please be sure to read reviews before download the apps from the store. These have been found while doing research for a new smart phone purchase. I do not have a droid to test on currently.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SmoothSync for Cloud Calendar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncs: calendars and reminders&lt;br /&gt;
Store Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dmfs.caldav.icloud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dmfs.caldav.icloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Description from Store: SmoothSync for Cloud Calendar syncs your iCloud calendars and reminders. Due to its implementation as sync adapter it integrates seamlessly with the native calendar app and widgets and operates invisible in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reminder For iCloud/iOS/iPhone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncs: Reminders&lt;br /&gt;
Store Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=us.doplus.reminder&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=us.doplus.reminder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Description from Store: This is a sole Android to-do reminder app that sync with Reminders of iCloud (iOS/Mac). All you have to do is creating a reminder on your phone and it will reminder you at the right time so that you won&#39;t miss any important task. It is designed to sync with the Reminder of iCloud. So, an iCloud account is needed before using this application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iNotes - Sync Note with iOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncs: notes&lt;br /&gt;
Store Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dayup.inotes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dayup.inotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Description from Store: iNotes is an easy notes app for synchronizing your notes of Android to Notes app on Mac/iOS(iphone, ipad) . It is currently applicable to iCloud, Gmail,Yahoo, Aol,163 only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SmoothSync for Cloud Contacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncs: Contacts&lt;br /&gt;
Store Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dmfs.carddav.icloud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dmfs.carddav.icloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Description from Store: SmoothSync for Cloud Contacts syncs your iCloud contacts. Due to its implementation as sync adapter it integrates seamlessly with the native contacts app and operates invisible in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iCloud Mail Sync&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;App: Blue Mail - Email &amp; Mailboxes&lt;br /&gt;
Store Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.trtf.blue&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.trtf.blue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Description from Store: Blue Mail is a free and universal email client allowing you to use and manage as many email accounts as you desire at the same time to create a powerful Unified Inbox experience with an extraordinary and modern design. Blue Mail supports Gmail, Yahoo, Office 365, AOL, Google Apps, Hotmail, Outlook, iCloud, Mail.ru, Zoho, GMX and any other IMAP mailbox!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative Option - Imap settings for icloud: &lt;a href=&quot;https://discussions.apple.com/thread/3636567?start=15&amp;tstart=0&quot; title=&quot;Setting up e-mail for Android?&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://discussions.apple.com/thread/3636567?start=15&amp;tstart=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iCloud HD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncs: seems to be a portal for icloud site (on tablets only)&lt;br /&gt;
Store Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.datheuma.icloud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.datheuma.icloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Description from Store: We present to you iCloud on Android. Access the iCloud control panel from the comfort of your Android tablet. Use your iCloud login and password to log in and you are ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus: Airplay Apps for Android&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following site has reviews on various airplay apps: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knowyourmobile.com/android-apps/18049/best-airplay-apps-android-gettin-dream-stream&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.knowyourmobile.com/android-apps/18049/best-airplay-apps-android-gettin-dream-stream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus: iCloud Bookmarks (iOS, PC and Mac Only)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncs: bookmarks (note untested on mobile android)&lt;br /&gt;
Store Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/icloud-bookmarks/fkepacicchenbjecpbpbclokcabebhah?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/icloud-bookmarks/fkepacicchenbjecpbpbclokcabebhah?hl=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Description from Store: iCloud stores your website bookmarks, so they are everywhere you go — on your iPhone, iPad, iPod touch, Mac, and PC. So when it comes to your devices, you can switch things up without mixing things up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/18/moving-from-an-ios-device-to-android-icloud/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/18/moving-from-an-ios-device-to-android-icloud/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Upcoming Github Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A frequently updated list of outstanding items to be added to the github repos.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Maps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try examples using font awesome in pop up box. Also try require js if successful on first attempt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHP Auction site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*email functionality (phase 1: user account info, phase 2: bid posted,profile changed, )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stronger password security and/or OAuth/twitter/facebook/google login.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replace icons with font awesome (and possibly utilize google fonts or type kit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding require js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding a map to show &quot;pick-up&quot; location. Will need to update DB (item)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add more variable checks in php and some in JS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upgrading to latest version of bootstrap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;countdown to auction close (Moment.JS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;password show/hide similar to iOS devices, strength meter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a way to change your password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap Master Pages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;link all pages together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add demo in azure to the read me file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check bootstrap snipes for ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap movie search:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix poster image (use a google query if needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look into way to see if its playing anywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use location api to get info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get log/lat and search google maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;link to youtube for easy access trailers or see if they can be puled from imdb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that user input is using latest tech and checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will become part of a library service or management system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add client side validation before submit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/17/upcoming-github-updates/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/17/upcoming-github-updates/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up Bluetooth on the raspberry pi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Setting up a bluetooth dongle can be quite interesting when using Raspmbc. Here is a guide on setting up.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth dongle (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.modmypi.com/nano-bluethooth-dongle?filter_name=bluetooth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;I used this one from ModMyPi&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wifi or ethernet connected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctheroux.com/2012/08/a-step-by-step-guide-to-setup-a-bluetooth-keyboard-and-mouse-on-the-raspberry-pi/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;following guide&lt;/a&gt; very helpful, however kept running into errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix it, run the following command after rebooting and before in place of installing bluetooth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install obex-data-server&lt;br /&gt;
apt-get ​install bluetooth bluez-utils blueman bluez-compat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have tried in the past to install bluetooth, but its still broken, run the below command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dpkg --configure -a&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there where problems pairing the device with the error message being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Creating device failed: org.bluez.Error.AuthenticationRejected: Authentication Rejected&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So following another article, it is recommended to type in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /usr/bin/bluez-simple-agent&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in this file, change &#39;KeyboardDisplay&#39; with &#39;DisplayYesNo&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctheroux.com/2012/08/a-step-by-step-guide-to-setup-a-bluetooth-keyboard-and-mouse-on-the-raspberry-pi/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Step by step Guide for setting up keyboard and mouse on Pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.correlatedcontent.com/blog/bluetooth-keyboard-on-the-raspberry-pi/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bluetooth keyboard on the Pi.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some bluetooth items will not work on Raspmbc such as audio. It has been suggested (Raspberry pi official forums) to instead use OpenELEC or Xbian. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/17/setting-up-bluetooth-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/03/17/setting-up-bluetooth-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quick Tip: Wordpress Development Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Stop wordpress updater by ftp.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per the following post, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sixfive.com.au/2012/10/wordpress-needs-to-access-your-web-server-please-enter-your-ftp-credentials-to-proceed/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wordpress needs access to your web server&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, you can prevent work press for asking for your ftp credentials when requesting an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the below lines to your wp.config.php file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
....&lt;br /&gt;
$method = &#39;direct&#39;;&lt;br /&gt;
define(&#39;FS_METHOD&#39;,&#39;direct&#39;);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/* That&#39;s all, stop editing! Happy blogging. */&lt;br /&gt;
...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Fix any issues with your (or another) plugin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a great plugin called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/log-deprecated-notices/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Log Deprecated Notices&lt;/a&gt;&quot; that aids in Wordpress development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just turn change WP_DEBUG to &#39;true&quot; and download the latest version from the above link. Once installed, it will be under: Tools &gt; Deprecated Calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deprecated call and line number will be displayed, along with an alternative to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This was only performed on a development machine. It is only recommended to do the above in a development environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/01/20/quick-tip-wordpress-development-tips/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jenntesolin.com/blog/2014/01/20/quick-tip-wordpress-development-tips/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
